Guide to the John Tabor Kempe Papers 1678-1782 (bulk 1752-1774) MS 344
New-York Historical Society
- Series 1: Court Case Records, 1678-1778 (bulk 1752-1774), and Undated, 1678-1778 and Undated
  - Subseries 4: Other Courts
    - Opinion, 1752 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Opinion on Captain Cosby's case. Crime occured under maritime juristiction.
    - The King vs. John Wiggins and John Concklin [owners of the sloop Mary], 1752 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Court of Vice Admirality
    - The King vs. Owner of the Spanish Negros, 1752 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Court of Vice-Admirality; Freedom case; On the same sheet as and filed under The King vs. Benjamin Moore and The King vs. Wiggins and Conklin.
    - William Ashburner vs. John Price: Complaint, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Court of Vixe-Admiralty
    - Herman Mentz and Peter Jansen [Janson] vs. The Sloop [?]: Libel for wages, 1759 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Name of the sloop unknown.
    - James Ayscough vs. The sloop Neptune: Libel, 1774 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Court of Vice-Admiralty
    - John Milligan vs. Thomas Brookman: Trespass, 1762 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Charles Kery vs. William Briggs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Alexander Colden qui tam vs. Brigantine Elizabeth and cargo, 1762 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - John Crew, the owners of the sloop Fox, and The King vs. Le Bon Rencontre: Libel, 1757 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Court of Vice Admiralty; Privateer cases with several claimants and interrelated suits kept together. See also Attorny General and The King vs. John Crew's claim. See also The Commissioners of the Admiralty vs. Bon Rencontre on behalf of the King.
    - John Hall vs. Thomas White, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Case involves the ship Charming Amy.
    - William Reed vs. The ship Ranger: Libel for wages, 1761 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - George Spencer qui tam vs. Francis Welch [Welsh] and Samuel Tingley, 1760 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Court of Vice-Admiralty. See other George Spencer cases in Court of Vice-Admiralty and Supreme Court of Judicature. See also correspondence from George Spencer to John Tabor Kempe. Case includes costs.
    - George Spencer qui tam vs. William Richardson: Libel, 1760-1762 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      See other George Spencer cases in Court of Vice-Admiralty and Supreme Court of Judicature. See correspondence from George Spencer to John Tabor Kempe. Case includes a reply to argument, plea, replication, notes, and costs.
    - Richard Swanweek [Swanwick] qui tam vs. Sloop Swallow and cargo: Libel, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Philadelphia; see correspondence for additional material.
    - The King vs. Jacob Vrooman: Rape, 1752 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Joseph Alberson: Forfeited recognizance, 1766 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      See also a letter from Devid Colden to John Tabor Kempe. Trial took place in Ulster County (NY General Sessions).
    - The King vs. Hugh Cairns [Cairins], 1763 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Albany County; See letter from John Tabor Kempe to Bradstreet dated January 10, 1763.
    - The King vs. William Humfrey [Humphrey]: Breach of duty, 1765 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Dutchess County; New York General Sessions; Breach of duty in case involving Isaac Lent, Abraham Lent, Jr., Andrias Mick, Korick Myers, and James Higbie [Higby]. See also a letter from John Tabor Kempe to Humphrey supporting his actions, dated January 14, 1765.
    - The King vs. James Briant: Debt, 1760 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      NY General Quarter Sessions
    - The King vs. John Cross for Mordecai Rietti: Debt, 1758-1759 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      New York General Quarter Sessions
    - The King vs. Edward Dillon: Breaking and entering, larceny, 1761 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Lewis DuBois: False Swearing, 1771 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Court of NY General Sessions in Dutchess County
    - The King vs. John Christopher, 1772 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - John Kip vs. Abraham Cock, 1762 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      New York General Quarter Sessions; Justices of the peace discharged John Kip from his apprenticeship with Abraham Cook on account of excessive cruelty.
    - The King vs. Lawrence and Cornelius Kortright, 1762 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      New York General Sessions.
    - The King vs. John McEnnory [McEnnery]: Assault, 1753 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      New York General Quarter Sessions; See also The King vs. Thomas Newton, John Smith, and Francis Boggs in Supreme Court of Judicature.
    - The King vs. Emanuel Myers and Levy Marks, 1754-1756 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Dutchess County; New York General Sessions
    - The King vs. Stephen Tippet, 1773 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      New York General Quarter Sessions; Erecting a fence on the property of Cornelius Bogardus.
    - The King vs. Thomas Tobias and Joseph Jadwin, 1772 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Queens County; New York General Sessions
    - The King vs. Nehemiah Browne, 1757 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Trial in New York General Sessions. Testimony of Timothy Wetmore. Case involves Hannah, an Indian servant taken from her master, Thomas Haviland, by her father Indian Joe and Nehemia Browne. See also Thomas Halivand to William Kempe, dated 26 Octiber, 1757. Haviland appealed to Kempe to try the case in Supreme Court of Judicature.
    - Jacob Remsen vs. John Samuel Smith, 1752-1753 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Also listed as argued in Kings County Court of Common Pleas.
    - Francis Warner vs. John Maclenan and Anthony Farmer: Trespass, 1766 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Marte Winne vs. Moses Emerson, 1756 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Albany County. See also the following correspondence: William Corry to Charles Hardy, December 30, 1755; William Corry to William Kempe, March 23, 1756; William Kempe to Charles Hardy, undated.
    - Richard Ayscough vs. Stephen Fitzpatrick: Larceny, 1759 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      NY Court of Mayor and Alderman
    - The King vs. John Hunt: Grand larceny, 1768 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Court of Oyer and Terminer.
    - The King vs. John Dupe: Burglary, 1768 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Court of Oyer and Terminer
    - The King vs. Cornelius Edison: Keeping disorderly/bawdy house and chimney a nuisance, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The King vs. Margaret McDermot: Grand larceny, 1768 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The King vs. Mary Cavenaugh: Keeping disorderly bawdy house, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The King vs. Elisha Cole: High treason, 1767 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Trial in Dutchess County through the Court of Oyer and Terminer. Case pertains to a riot in Dutchess County. See also The King vs. John Kane. Case includes notes on trial and subpeona.
    - The King vs. John Kane [Caine] [Cane] and others: Riot, 1765-1766 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Dutchess County; see also The King vs. Elisha Cole, Oyer, and Terminer, Dutchess County, for the same riot. Includes depositions against others involved in the riot, including William Prendergast [Pendergast]; Samuel Peters re: Robert Hughson, and Wiliam Prendergast [Pendergrass] [Prendergas].
    - The King vs. Thomas Woolley and Peter Harris, 1771 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The King vs. Paulus Snyder: Assault and battery, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stephen Rockwell vs. Nathan Taylor, 1772 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Dutchess County; Court of Common Please; Affidavit of Captain Nathan Taylor, requesting relief.
    - The King vs. William Van Nelsser, 1773 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Trial at Queens Assizes in Queens County. Case includes clerk's bill.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] James Lilley vs. [John Stiles] John Lamb: Ejectment, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Trial in Orange County at Court of Common Please. Case includes rule.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] James Lilley vs. [John Stiles] Hermanus Hanse: Ejectment, 1769 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Trial in Organge County at Court of Common Please. Case includes narratio.
    - Martin Ready vs. Joshua Lewis: Trespass and assault, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      The exact date of the case is unknown, but it appears to have taken place between 1760-1769.
    - Johannes New vs. Johannes Sharp, 1772-1773 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Prerogative Court
    - Glen & Schermerhorn, et al. vs. Trustees of Schenectady, 1773 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Hearing before Assembly.
    - James Degraw vs. Deet Luff Doren [Doring], 1754 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Court of Common Please in Kings County. Deposition of Simon Boerum, James Degraw, and Doren.
    - John Smyth vs. Stephen Skinner, 1774 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Middlesex County; New Jersey Supreme Court
    - Richard Mount, Thomas Mount, and William Vaughan vs. Oliver De Lancey and Henry Cuyler, 1774 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      New Jersey Court of Chancery
    - [John Denn ex dem] John Man [Mann], Mary Man, and Priscilla Bland vs. Lewis Morris Ashfield: Ejectment, 1769-1770 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Probably New Jersey Court of Chancery. See in the Alexander Papers: NJ Court of Chancery, 1773 Priscilla Bland, John and Mary Mann vs. Redford Ashfield et al. It appears John Tabor Kempe's opinion was sought on this case by a member of the Ashfield family.
    - Case of Peter Dorry, master of the sloop Sally, 1772 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Governor and Council
    - Case of Francis de Salas Cotilla, 1761 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Case of Francis de Salas Cortilla, a Spanish freeman who was taken prisoner and sold as a slave. See John Tabor Kempe to Lewis Morris, 12 February, 1761. Case includes order of council and petition.
    - Solomon Beby [Bebee] and others vs. John [Van] Renselaer: Land dispute, 1761-1762 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Governor and Council; Albany County; Appears to be hearing in Council. One document states Westonhook agt. Beby and others, then Reselaer agt. Beby and others on inside. May be countersuit; filed with this case. See also a letter from James Duane to Banyar November 29, 1761.
    - Property Case, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Governor and Council; case involving Ebenezer Jessup, attorny for Henry Stilson and the Proprietors of Kayaderosseras.
    - Affidavit of John Wetherhead, 1774 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Governor and Council; Estate case involving Johannes Montanje [Montanye] [Montanie], John Montanje, Joseph Montanje, Evardus Brouwer, Elizabeth Brown, Rachel Smith, Patrick Smith, and George Griffin.
    - Justice V. Sleyck and others vs. William Elsworth and John Dumond [Dumont], 1770-1771 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Trial in Governor and Council. The case seems to be of maladministration of justices of the peace. Case includes depositions and notes.
    - Thomas Swords vs. Corporation of Kingston: Land case, 1767 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Case in Governor and Council and includes notes for argument.
    - Rev. Gerhard Daniel Cock vs. Levi Pawling [Pauling] and Johannes Hardenbergh, 1764-1767 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Case over a dispute in the Protestant Dutch Church of Ulster County. See John Tabor Kempe to Pawling and Hardenbergh, dated 20 August, 1767. Case includes notes and answer.
    - John Bradstreet vs. Hardenburgh Patent, 1770 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Chief Daniel Nimham vs. Roger Morris, Philip Philipse, and Beverly Robinson, 1762-1765 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Dutchess County; Documents pertaining to the Wappinger Indian land claim; also the case of Samuel Monrow [Monroe], Nimham's guardian [The King vs. Monrow].
  - Subseries 5: Undetermined Courts
    - James Hawker qui tam vs. Theophilus Morgan, 1764 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Court of Vice Admiralty; claiment of nine hogsheads of rum and notice of taxing costs.
    - The King vs. Abraham, 1763 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Trial in Dutchess County. Affidavit of Bernard Doughty, constable. Abraham, slave of Peter Dewitt.
    - The King vs. David Brewer: Forgery, 1766 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. John Burnes: Keeping disorderly bawdy house, 1767 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Hugh Cairns [Cairins], 1763 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. James Campbell: Larceny (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Daniel and Vincent Carter, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Complaint of Sara Tealer.
    - The King vs. Henry Chase and John Churchill, 1766 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Trial in Dutchess County and includes affidavits.
    - The King vs. Thomas Clark and John Kendal: Riot, 1771 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Richard Clark, Mary Mulvaney, John McCourt, James Mitchel, Samuel Chesnut, Patrick Davit, Mary Chace, and John Higgins: Keeping disorderly bawdy house, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Case on the same sheet as The King vs. 8 Different Persons and includes presentments.
    - The King vs. John Connor: Grand larceny, 1773 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Samuel Connor: Keeping disorderly bawdy house, 1775 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Anthony Costigan: Grand larceny, 1771 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Stole money from Michael Genter.
    - The King vs. Mary Curten: Grand larceny, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      See also: The King vs. Mary Curtin for petit larceny 1770.
    - The King vs. Peggy Edwards and Jane Cooper: Receiving stolen goods, 1765 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Verdine Elsworth: Assault, 1765 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Bernard Gallagher, William Barr, Barney McDavit, and John McIver: Murder, 1769 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Case for the murder of Matthew Doyle.
    - The King vs. William Gill and George Bean: Grand larceny, 1769 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Mary Green: Petit larceny, 1774 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. William Griffin, 1769 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. James Groves: Grand larceny, 1769 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Charles Hamilton and others: Counterfeiting, 1761 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Dutchess County. See also: Letter from John Tabor Kempe to John Chambers dated May 1, 1761; James Livingston to John Chambers dated April 27, 1761; John Tabor Kempe to Clear Everit dated May 1, 1761; and John Tabor Kempe to Bartholomew Noxon dated April 26, 1761.
    - The King vs. Lawrence Harman: Assault, 1767 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. John Hennesy: Larceny, 1769 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Thomas Hicks, 1760 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Queens County
    - The King vs. Anthony Hill and Charles Hunt: Breach of peace, 1766 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Johannes Hogeboom and others: Riot and assault, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      List of persons who committed a riot and assault on Guysbert Jus. Sharp.
    - The King vs. Joseph Hubbs [Hubs]: False swearing, 1763 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Westchester County; memo also mentions Sarah McKinley and Anthony Lovelett.
    - The King vs. Jane Paterson: Petit larceny, 1771 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The King vs. Dirck Bratt: Grand larceny, 1769 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      On the same presentment as The King vs. John Jubeart. Case includes presentment.
    - The King vs. Peter Donally, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      On the same sheet as The King vs. John Lickens and Mary White.
    - The King vs. Mary Jacobs: Larceny, 1761 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. John Johnson, John Lemboiker, Daniel Chambers, Nathaniel Jean, Zoppar Jean, Henry Jean, Jacob Reader, John Clark, and others: Assault, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. John Jubeart: Passing counterfeit pieces of eight, 1769 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Pieces of eight is another name for the Spanish dollar. Case includes presentment.
    - The King vs. Peter Kenney: Petit larceny, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Daniel Kent: Burglary, 1770 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      On John Tabor Kempe's agenda, 1770.
    - The King vs. Ann Lavelly: Larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. James Lawson and John Croswell: Perjury, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Matthew Leake: Grand larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      On the same presentment as The King vs. Patrick McDavit.
    - The King vs. William Leisner: Murder, 1768 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Micajah Lewis et al.: Assault, 1768 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Deposition of Barbara Lyneall.
    - The King vs. John Lickens and Mary White: Highway Robbery, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Thomas Lynch, 1763 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Case regarding the sloop industry and includes an affidavit.
    - The King vs. Cornelius Lynsen: Assault, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Assault on John Graham.
    - The King vs. Joseph Mapes: Murder, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Orange County; Murder of John Campbell, "about four years old."
    - The King vs. Cornelius McCarty: Grand larceny, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Daniel McDaniel: Highway robbery, 1771 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      The victim of the highway robbery was John Harris.
    - The King vs. Patrick McDavit: Assault, 1768 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Michael McGary: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Catherine McMullin: Receiving stolen goods, 1770 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Charles Morgan, 1754 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Case in Westchester County. See also the following letters: J. King to William Kempe dated November 3, 1759; Charles Morgan to William Kempe dated September 3, 1754; Richard Cain to William Kempe dated August 26, 1754 and April 14, 1754. Case includes affidavits.
    - The King vs. William Morrell: Property damage, 1771 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. John Clayton Morris: Grand larceny, 1767-1768 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Two cases
    - The King vs. Charles Nicoll [Nicol], Jr.: Assault and battery, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Mother O'Neal [alias Smith]: Keeping disorderly bawdy house, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Benjamin Payne: Threat, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Edward Richmond, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. George Seares, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. William Thomas: Grand larceny, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Sarah Peters: Grand larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. Augustus Pennil: Killing a cow with intent to steal her hide, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The King vs. John Bryant: Larceny, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Case on the same presentment as The King vs. George Weght. Case includes presentment.
    - The King vs. Nicholas Rassong: Passing counterfeit coin, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. William Richartts: Larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Price Roach: Larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Patrick Rourk: Grand larceny, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Rudge, on complaint of Hallet: Assault, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Queens County; Other names include Edward Bowen and William Dugliss.
    - The King vs. John Ryen [Ryan]: Grand larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Scipio: Grand larceny, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Scipio, slave of Thomas Harden.
    - The King vs. Richard Shucksburgh: Nuisance, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Catherine Smith: Larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. John Smith, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. John Smith [alias John Bayley]: Breaking and entering, larceny, 1763 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      See legal executions, 1763, perhaps same case.
    - The King vs. Joshua Smith, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Zach[ariah] Smith Allen: Uttering counterfeit bills, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. William Stone: Larceny, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Elizabeth Stuart: Petit larceny, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. John Taylor: Assault, 1770-1771 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Assault on Joan Griffiths.
    - The King vs. Henry Vlock: Rape, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Presentment and evidence on the rape of Rosina Berkenmyer.
    - The King vs. Edward Waddon: Assault, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. William Wallace: Petit larceny, 1770 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Richard Roch [Rotes] [Roach]: Larceny, 1752 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Case includes examinations, presentment, and notes.
    - The King vs. William and Joseph Rodman: Assault, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Trial in Westchester County. Case includes presentment.
    - The King vs. John Moris Scott, John McKesson, and Gilbert Burger, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Case includes a statement of case by John Coghill Knapp.
    - The King vs. John Hamilton Stewart, Arthur Kane [McKane], and Elizabeth Kane: Grand larceny, 1769 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The King vs. Mary and Wyntje Walker, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Case for the assault of Ralph Thurman.
    - The King vs. George Weght: Uttering counterfeit bills, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Prudence Alinor vs. Isaac and Hannah Wood: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - John Beekman vs. Thomas White: Assault, 1758 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Witnesses include John Beekman, John Waddell, and Garrit Van Horne.
    - Beninga Sybilla Berckenmeyer vs. Jacob Freese et al, 1754 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Charge of breaking and entering, and larceny, in Albany County. Affidavit of Abraham Fonda and Henry Van Rensselaer. State of case mentions Nicholas Van Loon, John Van Loon and members of congregation of the Lutheran Church.
    - Stephen Bourk [Burk] vs. William Gort, 1756 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Complaint of assault.
    - Frederick Carmer vs. Hudson Goffe: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Frederick Carmer vs. Hudson Goffe: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - William Casey [Kasey] vs. Godfry Cunningham et al., 1754 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Ann and John Chambers [Chambon] vs. Henry Soper and Benjamin Boice, 1764 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Henry Chase vs. Samuel Shearman, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Case includes costs for plaintiff.
    - Peter Clows vs. John McNeal, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Richard Colden qui tam, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Note of seizure of 11 hhs of molasses and two boats.
    - Sarah Colford vs. Richard Vanderbergh, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - John Davis vs. Emanuel Smelliger [Smalliger] [Smaliger] [Smalege], 1769 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Ulster County; Davis vs. Smelliger original case. Smelliger then complained to John Tabor Kempe about the JPs involved in his case. Much of this material pertains to the complaint. See John Tabor Kempe to Charles Clinton, dated May 24, 1769 and June 13, 1769.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] De Lancey and others vs. Israel Ryers: Ejectment, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Case includes note.
    - William DeWitt vs. Elizabeth Jacobs, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - [John Denn ex dem] James Bunnel [Bonnell] vs. John Shotwell: Ejectment, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mary Ditchfield vs. Edward Stevens and his wife: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Anthony Dobbins vs. James Taggart et al, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Charles Doughty vs. Pugsleys and Leggett: Land dispute, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - James Downes [Duanes] vs. Francis Child, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Albany and Tryon Counties
    - Samuel Duke vs. William Faulkner, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Deposition, 1755 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Case between John Fenn and Joseph Wilson, not clear which is plaintiff and which is defendant.
    - Mary Coloil et al. vs. Devid Abeel [Abele] [Abale], Edward Early, and John Rodman, 1753 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Plaintiffs include Mary Coloil, Sarah Lyell, Ann Huddleston, and Elizabeth Hudleston, all the daughters of William Huddleston; Filed under Huddleston Property Dispute or Debt; Also involved were Joseph and William Morris.
    - Moses Franks vs. Thomas Grenell [Grennel], 1774 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Marthe Fry [Frye] vs. Vine Hatfield, Isiah Maynard, Bartholomew Gidney, Bethrah Knap, Samuel Owen, Martha Graham, and Elizabeth Knap: Riot, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Johanna Rosanna Glazier vs. John George Cook, 1756 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Jane Gold vs. William Haden and others: Assault, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 4)